export const topick4 = [
  {
    question: 'In what year was the Ostend Company founded?',
    options: {
      a: '1717',
      b: '1789',
      c: '1848',
    },
    answer: '1717',
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the main export of Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Grain',
      b: 'Fish',
      c: 'Silk',
    },
    answer: 'Silk',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which country was the main trading partner of Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Spain',
      b: 'China',
      c: 'Portugal',
    },
    answer: 'China',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year did Ostend gain the right to free trade?',
    options: {
      a: '1604',
      b: '1722',
      c: '1830',
    },
    answer: '1722',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What important product was imported to Ostend in the 19th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Silk',
      b: 'Spices',
      c: 'Timber',
    },
    answer: 'Spices',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which ship was the first merchant vessel from Ostend to cross the Atlantic?',
    options: {
      a: 'Count of Flanders',
      b: 'Santa Maria',
      c: 'Ostend Maru',
    },
    answer: 'Ostend Maru',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year was the first exchange in Ostend founded?',
    options: {
      a: '1670',
      b: '1725',
      c: '1801',
    },
    answer: '1725',
  },
  {
    question: 'What important trade deal was concluded in Ostend in 1838?',
    options: {
      a: 'Opening of the first railway line',
      b: 'Conclusion of a treaty with India',
      c: 'Establishment of the maritime college',
    },
    answer: 'Conclusion of a treaty with India',
  },
  {
    question: 'What was the main import of Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Silk',
      b: 'Tea',
      c: 'Gold',
    },
    answer: 'Tea',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year was the Ostend maritime exchange founded?',
    options: {
      a: '1601',
      b: '1701',
      c: '1801',
    },
    answer: '1801',
  },
];
